<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Text Mining for Information Professionals</title>
    <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Text Mining for Information Professionals</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 11:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://textmining-infopros.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of YouTube video contents on Koha and DSpace, and sentiment analysis of viewers’ comments</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter7/01-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter7/01-story/</guid>
      <description>In the last decade, we have seen the adoption of the latest technological innovations in the services provided by the library and information centres. The library professionals have adopted tools ranging from integrated library management software for managing housekeeping operations to developing institutional repositories using digital content management software&amp;hellip;..
  Authors   Vinit Kumar is an Assistant Professor at the Department of Library and Information Science, Babasaheb Bhimrao Ambedkar University, Lucknow who performed the following study in association with Maya Deori (Research Scholar) and Manoj Kumar Verma (Associate Professor) from the Department of Library and Information Science, Mizoram University, Aizawl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Language Processing (NLP) for Sensory Science</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter8/01-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter8/01-story/</guid>
      <description>The goal of our project, Seeing Flavors, is to take open-ended food descriptions and extract a descriptive sensory language through the application of Natural Language Processing (NLP) to published, free-text descriptions. A set of whiskey descriptions is used as a case study. This project is a collaborative effort between the Department of Food Science and Technology and University Libraries at Virginia Tech&amp;hellip;..
  Authors   Chreston Miller and Michael Stamper are the University Librarians at the Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Experience</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter3/01-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter3/01-story/</guid>
      <description>I learned regular expressions through a Library Carpentry workshop five years ago, and now hardly a day goes by when I do not use this tool to extract data from a text file or to reformat or clean data that I have scraped from a website&amp;hellip;.
  Author   Jordan Patterson is a Cataloguing and Metadata Librarian at the Memorial University Libraries, St. John&amp;rsquo;s, Newfoundland, Canada.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Experience</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter9/01-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter9/01-story/</guid>
      <description>I am the Data Visualization Librarian at UTA, and I work with students and faculty to help them develop skills in data visualization&amp;hellip;.
  Authors   Issac Williams is a University Librarian at the University of Texas, Arlington. He caters to the need for humanities, social sciences, stem, and professional discipline patrons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subject Evaluation for Collection Mappings</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter4/01-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter4/01-story/</guid>
      <description>At the University of North Texas Libraries, subject-based collections are evaluated on a rotating basis in order to ensure that the diverse needs of each academic department are being met. We start each review by researching the current program to understand the needs, particularly regarding subjects covered in curricula and research&amp;hellip;..
  Authors   Karen Harker and Sephra Byrne are University Librarians at the University of North Texas, Texas, United States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The SF Nexus</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter2/01-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter2/01-story/</guid>
      <description>The vast majority of twentieth-century literature remains undigitized, unavailable for access online even for the purposes of data analysis. The field of &amp;ldquo;distant reading&amp;rdquo; in literary criticism remains dependent upon impoverished datasets that are not representative of book history, especially mass-market genre fiction. We began a digitization project of mass-market science fiction at Temple University Libraries in the fall of 2017. We are currently expanding the project to include a range of special collections around the country with science fiction holdings&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Topic Networks in Personal Correspondence: The Richards/Turner Letters</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter5/01-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter5/01-story/</guid>
      <description>My story describes using a network visualization of an LDA topic model of correspondence (letters) between two early-20th-century female psychiatrists to discover and show how key concerns about work and home life are connected to other topics in the letters.
  Author   Nathaniel D. Porter is a University Librarian at the Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Virginia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leverage Undergraduate Student Researchers to Deliver Text Data Mining Services to Library Users</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter1/01-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter1/01-story/</guid>
      <description>To expand the reach and meet demand of consultation requests in Data Services at Virginia Tech (VT) University Libraries, a libraries-based undergraduate research program, that focuses on data consulting, was created. This group collectively reachers two major goals &amp;ndash; (1) enhance the research and teaching mission of the University and Libraries, and (2) have more humanpower available to complete detailed, embedded consultations that require specialized analysis and tools, like text-data mining&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Experience</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter4/02-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter4/02-story/</guid>
      <description>The work I do focuses on visualizing scholarly publication and citation data with VOSviewer, a software tool for visualizing bibliometric networks via exported files from bibliographic databases, such as Web of Science and Scopus. My story focuses mainly on using the tool to create term co-occurrence maps&amp;hellip;.
  Author   Rachel Miles is a University Librarian at Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Virginia, and caters to the need of humanities, social sciences, STEM, fine arts, and professional discipline users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Experience</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter8/02-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter8/02-story/</guid>
      <description>The University of Zambia (UNZA) has had a functional Institutional Repository (IR) for way over a decade now. One of the key digital objects ingested into the IR is Electronic Theses and Dissertations (ETDs)&amp;hellip;.
  Author   Lighton Phiri is a researcher at the University of Zambia, Zambia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Randall Library Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter9/02-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter9/02-story/</guid>
      <description>The Facts and Planning dashboard shows various data about Randall Library to our stakeholders and peers&amp;hellip;.
  Author   Marcella Fredriksson is a Web and Discovery Services Librarian at the University of North Carolina Wilmington.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of Minnesota: Text as Data Practice group</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter1/02-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter1/02-story/</guid>
      <description>Librarians at the University of Minnesota Twin Cities launched the Text as Data Practice Group after observing an increasing number of graduate students, staff, and faculty who were hoping to learn more about computational text analysis methods. While some disciplines embed computational research into their curriculum in some form, many students in the social sciences and humanities still have few options to engage with computational text analysis methods in the classroom&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yewno Discover: A Next Generation Research Tool</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter5/02-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter5/02-story/</guid>
      <description>I am sharing information about Yewno Discover, a next generation research tool that enables library patrons to go beyond keyword searching, by searching through concepts and visualisations. The technology was incubated at Stanford University in California and today we have academic institutions and public libraries using Yewno Discover. The roots of Yewno’s technology go back to 2009 where the founder of Yewno was doing a PhD at King&amp;rsquo;s College London in Econophysics creating an algorithm to read large amounts of structured and unstructured data&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constellate: Text Analytics Platform</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter2/02-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter2/02-story/</guid>
      <description>JSTOR and Portico are developing a text and data analytics service that provides &amp;ldquo;a platform for learning and performing text analysis, building datasets, and sharing analytics course materials&amp;rdquo; [a] (the beta release is at https://tdm-pilot.org/). This service opens the black box of text analysis: enabling librarians and faculty to teach it, students to learn it, and researchers to make discoveries using content from JSTOR, Portico, and other sources&amp;hellip;..
  Author   Amy J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing Enhanced Library OPAC through Text Analytics Tools: Integration of Koha and Voyant</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter1/03-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter1/03-story/</guid>
      <description>An OPAC is considered as the mirror of a library collection of any type or size. It has continued to evolve from card catalog to Web-OPAC through five different generations. This storyline aims to share an experience in enhancing the capabilities of a Web-OPAC through the integration of an open-source ILS and an open-source text analysis tool&amp;hellip;..
    Author     Parthasarathi Mukhopadhyay is a Professor at the Department of Library and Information science, University of Kalyan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TDM Working Group at the University Libraries at Virginia Tech</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter2/03-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter2/03-story/</guid>
      <description>As the Evidence Synthesis Librarian at the University Libraries at Virginia Tech I support evidence synthesis projects, such as systematic reviews. These projects are resource-intensive, requiring several contributors and skill-sets, typically taking one to three years for proper completion. Systematic reviews are intended for decision-making, so accuracy and efficiency are paramount. Thus, I am primarily interested in Text and Data Mining (TDM) methods to improve workflow and efficiency of evidence synthesis&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Roles of Tableau and TXT in a Pre/Post COVID Longitudinal Inquiry of Archival Labor Trends</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter9/03-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter9/03-story/</guid>
      <description>Most archival training programs require a hands-on practicum, particularly to ensure accreditation from ALA. Students are placed in an internship role at an institution in their community and encouraged to engage in reflective analysis of their experiences practicing archival theory hands-on. I completed Wayne State University’s MLIS program off-campus and virtually, prior to the Covid-19 pandemic shutting down the majority of &amp;ldquo;brick and mortar” GLAM and higher educational institutions. Many of my peers were quickly placed in university archives, with corporate partners, or in local historical agencies&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/about/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/about/about-me/</guid>
      <description>I am originally from Atlanta, Georgia, and am a proud ramblin&#39; wreck from Georgia Tech. I received my PhD in psychology and quantitative methods from Vanderbilt University in 2008. Prior to joining RStudio, I was an Assistant Professor at Arizona State University, and an Associate Professor at Oregon Health &amp;amp; Science University (OHSU). At OHSU, I was an NIH-funded Principal Investigator and an Assistant Center Director.
My research focused on health-related applications of Natural Language Processing-based methods, and was funded by the National Institutes of Health, the Oregon Clinical and Translational Research Institute, and Autism Speaks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduce yourself online with blogdown &amp; Hugo Apéro</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2021-iyo-tunis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2021-iyo-tunis/</guid>
      <description>A workshop for building a personal website from the comfort of RStudio using the blogdown R package, using a Hugo theme I developed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crafting Kind Tools</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2021-ares-kind-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2021-ares-kind-tools/</guid>
      <description>Whenever you use software, you are also using a tool that was crafted by someone else. Is it kind? Does it matter? What makes a tool kind?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making R Markdown work better for you</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2021-rmd-params/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2021-rmd-params/</guid>
      <description>Made with YAML, strings, and glue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take a Sad Plot &amp; Make It Better</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2021-rladies-jozi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2021-rladies-jozi/</guid>
      <description>Alison Hill (I think her unofficial nickname is RMarkdown Whisperer) is going to talk to us on another of her strengths. Making things beautiful, and informative. She&amp;rsquo;s going to do her &amp;ldquo;Take a Sad Plot &amp;amp; Make it Better&amp;rdquo; talk, for us. In this talk, Alison will discuss one plot’s life cycle, from a sad Powerpoint slide to the finished product made with the ggplot2 package in R, and what she learnt from it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduce yourself online</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2021-rstudio-global/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2021-rstudio-global/</guid>
      <description>A special workshop for rstudio::global() diversity scholars</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The download</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2020-larug/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2020-larug/</guid>
      <description>Recent updates in the R Markdown family</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>InspiRing InstRuction: A panel on teaching #rstats for all audiences</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2020-rladies-chicago-panel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2020-rladies-chicago-panel/</guid>
      <description>Come hear from 3 R-Ladies on how to make R pedagogy work for different groups of people!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Markdown for Pharma</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2020-rmd4pharma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2020-rmd4pharma/</guid>
      <description>A four-hour workshop for R / Pharma 2020 that will take you on a tour of how to get from data to manuscript using R Markdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning without a net</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2020-latinr-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2020-latinr-learn/</guid>
      <description>Aprendiendo sin una red</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching in Production</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2020-rstudio-tip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2020-rstudio-tip/</guid>
      <description>A 2-hour workshop for RStudio certified trainers on how to make shareable slides and websites with R Markdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RStudio Teaching in Production</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/rstudio-tip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/rstudio-tip/</guid>
      <description>A 2-hour workshop for RStudio certified trainers on how to make shareable slides and websites with R Markdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Machine Learning with the Tidyverse</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2020-rmedicine-tidyml/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2020-rmedicine-tidyml/</guid>
      <description>R / Medicine 2020: A 4-hour workshop to introduce the basics of machine learning in R using tidymodels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>palmerpenguins</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/palmerpenguins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/palmerpenguins/</guid>
      <description>An R data package with data about 3 penguin species from the Palmer Station in Antarctica</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to R Markdown for the CDC</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2020-rmd4cdc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2020-rmd4cdc/</guid>
      <description>A one-hour introduction to R Markdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>stat545.com</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/stat545.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/stat545.com/</guid>
      <description>A comprehensive course in data wrangling, exploration, and analysis with R</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tidymodels.org</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/tidymodels.org/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/tidymodels.org/</guid>
      <description>The central location for learning and using the tidymodels R packages</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharing on Short Notice</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2020-sharing-short-notice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2020-sharing-short-notice/</guid>
      <description>How to get your materials online on short notice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Machine Learning with the Tidyverse</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2020-rsc-tidyml/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2020-rsc-tidyml/</guid>
      <description>rstudio::conf(2020) two-day workshop to introduce the basics of machine learning and tidymodels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Machine Learning with the Tidyverse</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/tidyml/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/tidyml/</guid>
      <description>Introducing the basics of machine learning in R using tidymodels</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plot Twist: 10 Bake Offs, Visualized 11 Ways</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2019-rladies-sydney/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2019-rladies-sydney/</guid>
      <description>Using data from 10 series of The Great British Bake Off, we will walk through eleven ways to visualize the same data using the ggplot2 package. We&amp;rsquo;ll talk a lot about geoms and variable mappings, but also about what it means to &amp;ldquo;tidy your data&amp;rdquo;, plus the new pivot functions in the tidyr package.
You won&amp;rsquo;t need your laptops but you will get the most out of this talk if you know some basics about using ggplot2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Literate Projecting</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2019-ysc-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2019-ysc-keynote/</guid>
      <description>“Literate programming” is an approach to writing software programs that weaves together the source code and documentation at the time of creation. The idea is to create programs that are easier for users to understand. But they are also easier for programmers to work on and maintain. In this talk, I will describe how data scientists can be inspired by this programming approach and start what I refer to as “literate projecting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communicating with R Markdown Workshop</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2019-ysc-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2019-ysc-workshop/</guid>
      <description>A workshop for R Markdown users who want to get more out of R Markdown (and friends).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take a Sad Plot &amp; Make It Better</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2019-rladies-melbourne/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 18:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2019-rladies-melbourne/</guid>
      <description>In this talk, Alison will talk about one plot’s life cycle, from a sad Powerpoint slide to an Excel chart and finally to the finished product made with the ggplot2 package in R. Along the way, she will discuss why each version of the plot fails in different ways and how each iteration improved on the last one.
Latest event    This talk was most recently given at the University of South Wales on 2019/10/04.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Markdown for Medicine Workshop</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2019-rmed-rmd4medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2019-rmed-rmd4medicine/</guid>
      <description>Using R Markdown in an end-to-end workflow to go from data to manuscript</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Markdown for Medicine</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/rmd4medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/rmd4medicine/</guid>
      <description>A four-hour workshop that will take you on a tour of how to get from data to manuscript using R Markdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Students to Talk about Data Science</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2019-jsm-talk-ds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 14:00:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2019-jsm-talk-ds/</guid>
      <description>Data science educators have a unique opportunity to teach students the skills they need in their future careers. We know that practical skills matter, like being able to wrangle, explore, analyze, and visualize data (preferably using code), but what is easy to overlook is teaching students how to communicate about data science with other people. Being able to communicate about data, code, and insights gained are important skills we can strengthen in the classroom to make a real impact on students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer of blogdown: Day 04</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2019-summer-of-blogdown-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2019-summer-of-blogdown-04/</guid>
      <description>Putting the finishing touches on your blogdown site</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer of blogdown: Day 03</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2019-summer-of-blogdown-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2019-summer-of-blogdown-03/</guid>
      <description>Keeping up with your content</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer of blogdown: Day 02</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2019-summer-of-blogdown-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2019-summer-of-blogdown-02/</guid>
      <description>Personalizing your blogdown site</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer of blogdown: Day 01</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2019-summer-of-blogdown-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2019-summer-of-blogdown-01/</guid>
      <description>Create and deploy our first blogdown site &amp;ldquo;out-of-the-box&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using blogdown to Connect Beyond the Classroom</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2019-sdss-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2019-sdss-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Why and how to teach students to create their own website</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Us</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:38:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder
Formspree requires a (free) account and new form to be set up. The link is made on the final published url in the field: Restrict to Domain. It is possible to register up to 2 emails free and you can select which one you want the forms to go to within Formspree in the Settings tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet blogdown</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2019-rsc-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2019-rsc-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Making websites in R Markdown</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet bookdown</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2019-rsc-bookdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2019-rsc-bookdown/</guid>
      <description>Making books in R Markdown</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet flexdashboard</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2019-rsc-flexdashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2019-rsc-flexdashboard/</guid>
      <description>Making dashboards in R Markdown</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet xaringan</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2019-rsc-xaringan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2019-rsc-xaringan/</guid>
      <description>Making slides in R Markdown</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization in the Tidyverse</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2018-uo-plotoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2018-uo-plotoff/</guid>
      <description>Using one dataset from The Great British Bake Off, I show eleven ways to visualize one dataset using eleven different versions of &amp;ldquo;tidy data.&amp;rdquo; Take-away messages:
 Tidy data is the start of your data wrangling journey, not the end There is not a single &amp;ldquo;tidy&amp;rdquo; version of a dataset Tidy data does make you more nimble!  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LICENSE: CC-BY-SA</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/license/</guid>
      <description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Magic with R: Creative Learning Beyond Fear</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2018-cascadia-bigmagic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2018-cascadia-bigmagic/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by the book “Big Magic: Creative Living Beyond Fear” by Elizabeth Gilbert, Alison will talk about the five essential ingredients needed to creatively learn R and why these elements are also essential for advanced users to take their R skills to the next level. You will hear practical advice for when, where, and how to start a project in R, and how your learning can add value- both to your own knowledge and to contribute to the larger community of R learners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take a Sad Plot &amp; Make It Better</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2018-ohsu-sad-plot-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2018-ohsu-sad-plot-better/</guid>
      <description>Join us on April 6 for a walk-through of how to take a sad plot and make it better by Alison Hill, who co-teaches the CS631 Data Visualization course. Alison will take us through one plot’s life cycle, from a sad Powerpoint slide to an Excel chart and finally to the finished product made with the ggplot2 package in R. We will discuss why each version of the plot fails in different ways, how each iteration improved on the last one, and which data visualization principles are at work in the final plot to communicate a clear scientific story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labhub Workshop</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2017-ohsu-labhub/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2017-ohsu-labhub/</guid>
      <description>The landscape of scientific communication is changing dramatically. Diverse stakeholders, including major funders and universities are demonstrating a growing interest and investment in open scientific principles and practices. Researchers, students, and the institutions that support them are needing to navigate new expectations, workflows, and policies against a backdrop of relatively unchanged means and measures of scientific success.
Sound complicated? Join us on December 8th from 3:00 to 4:00 PM for a panel discussion with OHSU leaders and early career researchers on the evolving landscape of scientific communication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Up &amp; Running with blogdown</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/up-running-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/up-running-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>A workshop to get up and running with blogdown, GitHub, and Netlify</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Up &amp; Running with blogdown</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2017-pdxr-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2017-pdxr-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>See project links for more details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Your Graph Workshop</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2016-ohsu-dataviz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/talk/2016-ohsu-dataviz/</guid>
      <description>   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RLadies xaringan theme</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/rladies-xaringan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/rladies-xaringan/</guid>
      <description>An RLadies theme for slides made with the xaringan R package</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer of blogdown</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/summer-of-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/summer-of-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>A week of the blogdown R package for RStudio&amp;rsquo;s summer 2019 interns</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authors</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/authors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/authors/</guid>
      <description>Manika Lamba    Manika Lamba is a Ph.D. candidate at the Department of Library and Information Science, University of Delhi, India. She is currently serving as the Editor-in-Chief of the International Journal of Library and Information Services (IJLIS), the Elected Standing Committee Member for IFLA Science and Technology Libraries Section, and Newsletter Officer for ASIS&amp;amp;T South Asia Chapter. She was Editor-at-large for dh+lib (an ACRL Digital Humanities Interest Group project) and was featured in the Information Professionals Share their Top Tips for 2019 blog by the Copyright Clearance Center (CCC).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
