<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Text Mining for Information Professionals</title>
    <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Text Mining for Information Professionals</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://textmining-infopros.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of YouTube video contents on Koha and DSpace, and sentiment analysis of viewers’ comments</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter7/01-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter7/01-story/</guid>
      <description>In the last decade, we have seen the adoption of the latest technological innovations in the services provided by the library and information centres. The library professionals have adopted tools ranging from integrated library management software for managing housekeeping operations to developing institutional repositories using digital content management software&amp;hellip;..
  Authors   Vinit Kumar is an Assistant Professor at the Department of Library and Information Science, Babasaheb Bhimrao Ambedkar University, Lucknow who performed the following study in association with Maya Deori (Research Scholar) and Manoj Kumar Verma (Associate Professor) from the Department of Library and Information Science, Mizoram University, Aizawl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Language Processing (NLP) for Sensory Science</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter8/01-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter8/01-story/</guid>
      <description>The goal of our project, Seeing Flavors, is to take open-ended food descriptions and extract a descriptive sensory language through the application of Natural Language Processing (NLP) to published, free-text descriptions. A set of whiskey descriptions is used as a case study. This project is a collaborative effort between the Department of Food Science and Technology and University Libraries at Virginia Tech&amp;hellip;..
  Authors   Chreston Miller and Michael Stamper are the University Librarians at the Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Experience</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter3/01-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter3/01-story/</guid>
      <description>I learned regular expressions through a Library Carpentry workshop five years ago, and now hardly a day goes by when I do not use this tool to extract data from a text file or to reformat or clean data that I have scraped from a website&amp;hellip;.
  Author   Jordan Patterson is a Cataloguing and Metadata Librarian at the Memorial University Libraries, St. John&amp;rsquo;s, Newfoundland, Canada.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Experience</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter9/01-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter9/01-story/</guid>
      <description>I am the Data Visualization Librarian at UTA, and I work with students and faculty to help them develop skills in data visualization&amp;hellip;.
  Authors   Issac Williams is a University Librarian at the University of Texas, Arlington. He caters to the need for humanities, social sciences, stem, and professional discipline patrons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subject Evaluation for Collection Mappings</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter4/01-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter4/01-story/</guid>
      <description>At the University of North Texas Libraries, subject-based collections are evaluated on a rotating basis in order to ensure that the diverse needs of each academic department are being met. We start each review by researching the current program to understand the needs, particularly regarding subjects covered in curricula and research&amp;hellip;..
  Authors   Karen Harker and Sephra Byrne are University Librarians at the University of North Texas, Texas, United States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The SF Nexus</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter2/01-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter2/01-story/</guid>
      <description>The vast majority of twentieth-century literature remains undigitized, unavailable for access online even for the purposes of data analysis. The field of &amp;ldquo;distant reading&amp;rdquo; in literary criticism remains dependent upon impoverished datasets that are not representative of book history, especially mass-market genre fiction. We began a digitization project of mass-market science fiction at Temple University Libraries in the fall of 2017. We are currently expanding the project to include a range of special collections around the country with science fiction holdings&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Topic Networks in Personal Correspondence: The Richards/Turner Letters</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter5/01-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter5/01-story/</guid>
      <description>My story describes using a network visualization of an LDA topic model of correspondence (letters) between two early-20th-century female psychiatrists to discover and show how key concerns about work and home life are connected to other topics in the letters.
  Author   Nathaniel D. Porter is a University Librarian at the Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Virginia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leverage Undergraduate Student Researchers to Deliver Text Data Mining Services to Library Users</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter1/01-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter1/01-story/</guid>
      <description>To expand the reach and meet demand of consultation requests in Data Services at Virginia Tech (VT) University Libraries, a libraries-based undergraduate research program, that focuses on data consulting, was created. This group collectively reachers two major goals &amp;ndash; (1) enhance the research and teaching mission of the University and Libraries, and (2) have more humanpower available to complete detailed, embedded consultations that require specialized analysis and tools, like text-data mining&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Experience</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter4/02-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter4/02-story/</guid>
      <description>The work I do focuses on visualizing scholarly publication and citation data with VOSviewer, a software tool for visualizing bibliometric networks via exported files from bibliographic databases, such as Web of Science and Scopus. My story focuses mainly on using the tool to create term co-occurrence maps&amp;hellip;.
  Author   Rachel Miles is a University Librarian at Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Virginia, and caters to the need of humanities, social sciences, STEM, fine arts, and professional discipline users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Experience</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter8/02-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter8/02-story/</guid>
      <description>The University of Zambia (UNZA) has had a functional Institutional Repository (IR) for way over a decade now. One of the key digital objects ingested into the IR is Electronic Theses and Dissertations (ETDs)&amp;hellip;.
  Author   Lighton Phiri is a researcher at the University of Zambia, Zambia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Randall Library Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter9/02-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter9/02-story/</guid>
      <description>The Facts and Planning dashboard shows various data about Randall Library to our stakeholders and peers&amp;hellip;.
  Author   Marcella Fredriksson is a Web and Discovery Services Librarian at the University of North Carolina Wilmington.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of Minnesota: Text as Data Practice group</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter1/02-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter1/02-story/</guid>
      <description>Librarians at the University of Minnesota Twin Cities launched the Text as Data Practice Group after observing an increasing number of graduate students, staff, and faculty who were hoping to learn more about computational text analysis methods. While some disciplines embed computational research into their curriculum in some form, many students in the social sciences and humanities still have few options to engage with computational text analysis methods in the classroom&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yewno Discover: A Next Generation Research Tool</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter5/02-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter5/02-story/</guid>
      <description>I am sharing information about Yewno Discover, a next generation research tool that enables library patrons to go beyond keyword searching, by searching through concepts and visualisations. The technology was incubated at Stanford University in California and today we have academic institutions and public libraries using Yewno Discover. The roots of Yewno’s technology go back to 2009 where the founder of Yewno was doing a PhD at King&amp;rsquo;s College London in Econophysics creating an algorithm to read large amounts of structured and unstructured data&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constellate: Text Analytics Platform</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter2/02-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter2/02-story/</guid>
      <description>JSTOR and Portico are developing a text and data analytics service that provides &amp;ldquo;a platform for learning and performing text analysis, building datasets, and sharing analytics course materials&amp;rdquo; [a] (the beta release is at https://tdm-pilot.org/). This service opens the black box of text analysis: enabling librarians and faculty to teach it, students to learn it, and researchers to make discoveries using content from JSTOR, Portico, and other sources&amp;hellip;..
  Author   Amy J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing Enhanced Library OPAC through Text Analytics Tools: Integration of Koha and Voyant</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter1/03-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter1/03-story/</guid>
      <description>An OPAC is considered as the mirror of a library collection of any type or size. It has continued to evolve from card catalog to Web-OPAC through five different generations. This storyline aims to share an experience in enhancing the capabilities of a Web-OPAC through the integration of an open-source ILS and an open-source text analysis tool&amp;hellip;..
    Author     Parthasarathi Mukhopadhyay is a Professor at the Department of Library and Information science, University of Kalyan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TDM Working Group at the University Libraries at Virginia Tech</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter2/03-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter2/03-story/</guid>
      <description>As the Evidence Synthesis Librarian at the University Libraries at Virginia Tech I support evidence synthesis projects, such as systematic reviews. These projects are resource-intensive, requiring several contributors and skill-sets, typically taking one to three years for proper completion. Systematic reviews are intended for decision-making, so accuracy and efficiency are paramount. Thus, I am primarily interested in Text and Data Mining (TDM) methods to improve workflow and efficiency of evidence synthesis&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Roles of Tableau and TXT in a Pre/Post COVID Longitudinal Inquiry of Archival Labor Trends</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter9/03-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter9/03-story/</guid>
      <description>Most archival training programs require a hands-on practicum, particularly to ensure accreditation from ALA. Students are placed in an internship role at an institution in their community and encouraged to engage in reflective analysis of their experiences practicing archival theory hands-on. I completed Wayne State University’s MLIS program off-campus and virtually, prior to the Covid-19 pandemic shutting down the majority of &amp;ldquo;brick and mortar” GLAM and higher educational institutions. Many of my peers were quickly placed in university archives, with corporate partners, or in local historical agencies&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Dashboard using R</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/dashboard/</guid>
      <description>About     Chapter 9: Information Visualization covers the case study on Build a Dashboard using R.
How to Cite      
Please cite this compendium as: Lamba, Manika &amp;amp; Madhusudhan, Margam. (2021). Build a Dashboard using R (Version v1.0). http://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.5111093
Contents     The compendium contains the code associated with the case study. The flexboard_R.Rmd file contains the R code for the case study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burst Detection</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/burst-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/burst-detection/</guid>
      <description>About     Chapter 6: Burst Detection covers the case study on Burst Detection of Documents using Two Different Tools. It is divided into two parts: 6A, and 6B. 6A case study uses Sci-2 tool, whereas 6B case study uses R programming language to perform burst detection.
How to Cite      
Please cite this compendium as: Lamba, Manika, &amp;amp; Madhusudhan, Margam. (2021). Burst Detection of Documents using Three Different Tools (Version 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clustering</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/clustering/</guid>
      <description>About     Chapter 1: The Computational Library covers the case study on Clustering of Documents using Two Different Tools. It is divided into two parts: 1A, and 1B. 1A case study uses Orange tool whereas 1B case study uses R programming language to perform clustering.
How to Cite      
Please cite this compendium as: Lamba, Manika, &amp;amp; Madhusudhan, Margam. (2021). Clustering of Documents using Two Different Tools (Version 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Text Analysis</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/network-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/network-analysis/</guid>
      <description>About     Chapter 5: Network Text Analysis covers the case study on Network Text Analysis of Documents using Two Different R Packages. It is divided into two parts: 5A, and 5B. Both 5A and 5B case studies use R programming language to perform text network analysis but with different packages.
How to Cite      
Please cite this compendium as: Lamba, Manika, &amp;amp; Madhusudhan, Margam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predictive Modeling</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/predictive-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/predictive-modeling/</guid>
      <description>About     Chapter 8: Predictive Modeling covers the case study on Predictive Modeling of Documents using RapidMiner.
How to Cite      
Please cite this compendium as: Lamba, Manika, &amp;amp; Madhusudhan, Margam. (2021). Predictive Modeling of Documents using RapidMiner (Version 1.0). http://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.5090232
Contents     The compendium contains the data, code, and notebook associated with the case study. The 8a_dataset file contains the data and RapidMiner platform was used to perform the case study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment Analysis</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/sentiment-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/sentiment-analysis/</guid>
      <description>About     Chapter 7: Sentiment Analysis covers the case study on Sentiment Analysis of Documents using Two Different Tools. It is divided into two parts: 7A, and 7B. 7A case study uses RapidMiner, whereas 7B case study uses R programming language to perform sentiment analysis.
How to Cite      
Please cite this compendium as: Lamba, Manika, &amp;amp; Madhusudhan, Margam. (2021). Sentiment Analysis of Documents using Two Different Tools (Version 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic Modeling</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/topic-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/project/topic-modeling/</guid>
      <description>About     Chapter 4: Topic Modeling covers the case study on Topic Modeling of Documents using Three Different Tools. It is divided into three parts: 4A, 4B, and 4C. 4A case study uses Topic-Modeling-Tool, 4B case study uses RapidMiner, and 4C case study uses R programming language to perform topic modeling.
How to Cite      
Please cite this compendium as: Lamba, Manika, &amp;amp; Madhusudhan, Margam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Us</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:38:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder
Formspree requires a (free) account and new form to be set up. The link is made on the final published url in the field: Restrict to Domain. It is possible to register up to 2 emails free and you can select which one you want the forms to go to within Formspree in the Settings tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LICENSE: CC-BY-SA</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/license/</guid>
      <description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authors</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/authors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/authors/</guid>
      <description>Manika Lamba               
Manika Lamba is a Ph.D. candidate at the Department of Library and Information Science, University of Delhi, India. She is currently serving as the Editor-in-Chief of the International Journal of Library and Information Services (IJLIS), the Elected Standing Committee Member for IFLA Science and Technology Libraries Section, and Newsletter Officer for ASIS&amp;amp;T South Asia Chapter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
