<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chapter 1 on Text Mining for Information Professionals</title>
    <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/stories/chapter1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chapter 1 on Text Mining for Information Professionals</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://textmining-infopros.github.io/stories/chapter1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Leverage Undergraduate Student Researchers to Deliver Text Data Mining Services to Library Users</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/stories/chapter1/01-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/stories/chapter1/01-story/</guid>
      <description>To expand the reach and meet demand of consultation requests in Data Services at Virginia Tech (VT) University Libraries, a libraries-based undergraduate research program, that focuses on data consulting, was created. This group collectively reachers two major goals &amp;ndash; (1) enhance the research and teaching mission of the University and Libraries, and (2) have more humanpower available to complete detailed, embedded consultations that require specialized analysis and tools, like text-data mining&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of Minnesota: Text as Data Practice group</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/stories/chapter1/02-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/stories/chapter1/02-story/</guid>
      <description>Librarians at the University of Minnesota Twin Cities launched the Text as Data Practice Group after observing an increasing number of graduate students, staff, and faculty who were hoping to learn more about computational text analysis methods. While some disciplines embed computational research into their curriculum in some form, many students in the social sciences and humanities still have few options to engage with computational text analysis methods in the classroom&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing Enhanced Library OPAC through Text Analytics Tools: Integration of Koha and Voyant</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/stories/chapter1/03-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/stories/chapter1/03-story/</guid>
      <description>An OPAC is considered as the mirror of a library collection of any type or size. It has continued to evolve from card catalog to Web-OPAC through five different generations. This storyline aims to share an experience in enhancing the capabilities of a Web-OPAC through the integration of an open-source ILS and an open-source text analysis tool&amp;hellip;..
    Author     Parthasarathi Mukhopadhyay is a Professor at the Department of Library and Information science, University of Kalyan.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
