<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chapter 5 on Text Mining for Information Professionals</title>
    <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/stories/chapter5/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chapter 5 on Text Mining for Information Professionals</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://textmining-infopros.github.io/stories/chapter5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Topic Networks in Personal Correspondence: The Richards/Turner Letters</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/stories/chapter5/01-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/stories/chapter5/01-story/</guid>
      <description>My story describes using a network visualization of an LDA topic model of correspondence (letters) between two early-20th-century female psychiatrists to discover and show how key concerns about work and home life are connected to other topics in the letters.
  Author   Nathaniel D. Porter is a University Librarian at the Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Virginia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yewno Discover: A Next Generation Research Tool</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/stories/chapter5/02-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/stories/chapter5/02-story/</guid>
      <description>I am sharing information about Yewno Discover, a next generation research tool that enables library patrons to go beyond keyword searching, by searching through concepts and visualisations. The technology was incubated at Stanford University in California and today we have academic institutions and public libraries using Yewno Discover. The roots of Yewno’s technology go back to 2009 where the founder of Yewno was doing a PhD at King&amp;rsquo;s College London in Econophysics creating an algorithm to read large amounts of structured and unstructured data&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
