<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chapter 2 on Text Mining for Information Professionals</title>
    <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chapter 2 on Text Mining for Information Professionals</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The SF Nexus</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter2/01-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter2/01-story/</guid>
      <description>The vast majority of twentieth-century literature remains undigitized, unavailable for access online even for the purposes of data analysis. The field of &amp;ldquo;distant reading&amp;rdquo; in literary criticism remains dependent upon impoverished datasets that are not representative of book history, especially mass-market genre fiction. We began a digitization project of mass-market science fiction at Temple University Libraries in the fall of 2017. We are currently expanding the project to include a range of special collections around the country with science fiction holdings&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constellate: Text Analytics Platform</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter2/02-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter2/02-story/</guid>
      <description>JSTOR and Portico are developing a text and data analytics service that provides &amp;ldquo;a platform for learning and performing text analysis, building datasets, and sharing analytics course materials&amp;rdquo; [a] (the beta release is at https://tdm-pilot.org/). This service opens the black box of text analysis: enabling librarians and faculty to teach it, students to learn it, and researchers to make discoveries using content from JSTOR, Portico, and other sources&amp;hellip;..
  Author   Amy J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TDM Working Group at the University Libraries at Virginia Tech</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter2/03-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter2/03-story/</guid>
      <description>As the Evidence Synthesis Librarian at the University Libraries at Virginia Tech I support evidence synthesis projects, such as systematic reviews. These projects are resource-intensive, requiring several contributors and skill-sets, typically taking one to three years for proper completion. Systematic reviews are intended for decision-making, so accuracy and efficiency are paramount. Thus, I am primarily interested in Text and Data Mining (TDM) methods to improve workflow and efficiency of evidence synthesis&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
