<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chapter 9 on Text Mining for Information Professionals</title>
    <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter9/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chapter 9 on Text Mining for Information Professionals</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter9/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Personal Experience</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter9/01-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter9/01-story/</guid>
      <description>I am the Data Visualization Librarian at UTA, and I work with students and faculty to help them develop skills in data visualization&amp;hellip;.
  Authors   Issac Williams is a University Librarian at the University of Texas, Arlington. He caters to the need for humanities, social sciences, stem, and professional discipline patrons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Randall Library Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter9/02-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter9/02-story/</guid>
      <description>The Facts and Planning dashboard shows various data about Randall Library to our stakeholders and peers&amp;hellip;.
  Author   Marcella Fredriksson is a Web and Discovery Services Librarian at the University of North Carolina Wilmington.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Roles of Tableau and TXT in a Pre/Post COVID Longitudinal Inquiry of Archival Labor Trends</title>
      <link>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter9/03-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://textmining-infopros.github.io/collection/chapter9/03-story/</guid>
      <description>Most archival training programs require a hands-on practicum, particularly to ensure accreditation from ALA. Students are placed in an internship role at an institution in their community and encouraged to engage in reflective analysis of their experiences practicing archival theory hands-on. I completed Wayne State University’s MLIS program off-campus and virtually, prior to the Covid-19 pandemic shutting down the majority of &amp;ldquo;brick and mortar” GLAM and higher educational institutions. Many of my peers were quickly placed in university archives, with corporate partners, or in local historical agencies&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
